Inventory of the Harry Roswell Hill papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Harry Roswell Hill papers
1920-1949
1942-1946
97018
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box, 1 oversize box (1.3 linear feet)
Personnel records, orders, letters, manuals, servicemen's newspapers, clippings, other printed matter, photographs, and miscellany relating to American military railway service operations in Iran and elsewhere in the Persian Gulf Command during World War II.
Hill, Harry Roswell, 1899-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1997.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Captain, United States Army Transportation Corps; member, 762nd Railway Shop Battalion, 1942-1946.
Scope and Content of Collection
Personnel records, orders, letters, manuals, servicemen's newspapers, clippings, other printed matter, photographs, and miscellany relating to American military railway service operations in Iran and elsewhere in the Persian Gulf Command during World War II.
World War, 1939-1945--Transportation.; World War, 1939-1945--Middle East.; Railroads--Iran.; United States. Army. Railway Shop Battalion, 762nd.
- Service record, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Service in Persian Gulf Command materials, 1942-1945 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes memoranda, orders, invitations, passes, certificates, receipts, and ephemera relating to Hill's service in Iran and time spent in Palestine, Germany, and Paris on leave or in connection with his Army service. Also includes a small amount of material related to Claude Hovis, Hill's roommate, who was killed in Iran.
- Agenda book and calendars, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 1: 3)
- Correspondence, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  Between Hill and his wife, Martha (Marty).
- Photographs, undated (Box-folder 1: 5)
  French Foreign Legion headquarters, Sidi Bel Abbès, Algeria (2 photos); unidentified Army men getting water from barrels in desert (1 photo); and 60th Operations group in front of C-47 aircraft, possibly at Tafaraoui Airfield, Algeria (1 photo).
- Printed matter, 1920-1949
  - Germany, 1942, 1944 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - India, Iraq, Libya, Syria, 1942, undated (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Iran - guides, 1942-1943, undated (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Iran, Middle and Near East - maps, undated (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Iran/Persian Gulf Command - clippings, 1943-1944, undated (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Palestine, 1944, undated (Box-folder 1: 11)
    Includes maps, tour information, and newsletters collected by Hill in relation to leave taken in Palestine.
  - Paris, 1943, 1945, undated (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Railway service, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 1: 13)
    Includes materials specifically related to the 762nd Railway Shop Battalion.
  - United States Army, general, 1943, 1945, undated (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Manuals, 1920, 1944 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Miscellaneous, 1949, undated (Box-folder 1: 16)
- Oversize material, 1937-1945
  - The National Geographic Magazine, Vol. 84, No. 2, 1943 August (Box-folder 2: 1)
    Includes article titled "Iran in Wartime."
  - Persian Gulf Command, undated
    Brief pictorial record of Persian Gulf region. Includes standardized letter to all individuals who served in Persian Gulf Command from Brigadier General Donald P. Booth.
  - Souvenir of an Accomplishment, 1944
    Photo booklet recognizing American railroad efforts in Iran to bring supplies to Russians in World War II.
  - Yank, The Army Weekly, Persian Gulf edition, Vol. 1, No. 18, excerpt, 1943 December 15
  - The Saturday Evening Post, excerpt, 1944 September 2
  - Attack, excerpt, 1944 July
    Includes article titled "Men of the 762nd Find Time for Recreation Now."
  - Egyptian Mail, No. 9681, excerpt, 1945 May 29
  - Sandscript, Vol. 3, No. 19, 1945 May 26
  - [Shaypour?] magazine, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Krokodil (Moscow), No. 26-27, 1943
  - Voici comment la VIIIème Armée battit les Allemandes et fit crouler l'Empire Africain de Mussolini, undated
  - La guerre illustrée, L.T.A. Robinson, Ltd. (London), 1943 March
  - "Gmunden [Austria]: Das tor ins Salzkammergut," tourist map, 1940 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - "Gmunden [Austria], Ostmark, Deutschland," tourist map, undated
  - "Old Persia, Modern Iran," illustrated map, undated
  - "Cartographical Map of Iran, Once Known as Persia, Showing Many Places of Biblical and Historical Interest," Persian Gulf Command, illustrated map, circa 1944
  - "Iran," TWA travel poster, undated (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - "Deep in Iran, Alco-G.E. Diesel-electric Locomotives Haul Supplies to Russia," General Electric poster, undated
  - "New Songs," songbook of compositions from Iranian composer Ahmad Furutan Rad, 1937
  - Algérie, edition de l'OFALAC [Office algérien d'action économique et touristique], undated (Box-folder 2: 5)